# Mitchell Stride

# **Electronics Engineering Student Embedded Systems | PCB Dev.**

30+ Unique PCB designs. Interested in electronics for embedded applications. Specialized in microcontroller based PCB Design. Experienced with electronics DVT and system instrumentation.

mstride@mun.ca mitchellstride.com +1(709) 541-3744 St. John's, NL, CAN

# **Work Experience**

#### Hardware Design Engineer - Co-op

Mysa Smart Thermostats - IOT Hardware Sept 2020 - Dec 2020 St. John's, NL

- ⇒ Custom FT2232H USB2.0 HS to UART/JTAG programmer utilizing basic SI for series terminations, impedance, and length matching.
- ⇒ Test jig/fixture bed of nails PCB design for production.

#### **Hardware Verification Engineer – Co-op**

Nokia – Telecommunications Hardware

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020 & Jan 2017 - Apr 2017 | Ottawa, ON

- ⇒ Created verification test plans to execute in the lab. Provided schematic and routing feedback to lead designers.
- ⇒ Drafted ECOs to rework PCBs and optimize manufacturing.
- ⇒ Reworked complex HDI designs with 0201 size passives.
- ⇒ High current, multi phase, power supply stability testing.
- ⇒ Automated test scripting over telnet using Perl.

#### **Hardware Design Engineer – Co-op**

Curtiss-Wright - Embedded Defense Solutions Jan 2019 - Apr 2019 Ottawa, ON

- ⇒ Performed schematic, layout, and routing reviews for complex Intel and PowerPC based single board computers.
- ⇒ Created and performed DVT test plans on high speed signals using a 16GHz scope.

#### **Embedded Systems Engineer – Co-op**

Kraken Robotics Inc. – Underwater Sonar & Robotics Apr 2018 - Aug 2018 | St. John's, NL

- ⇒ Designed 10+ PCBs and 2 embedded stacks for underwater robotics in rugged environments using KiCAD.
- ⇒ Evaluated solutions in the lab using rapid prototyping techniques with STM32 Nucleo development boards.

#### **Cross Asset Engineering Assistant**

ExxonMobil – Upstream Instrumentation & Controls Sept 2017 - Dec 2017 | St. John's, NL

- ⇒ Designed analog and digital logic to optimize the Electrical Power Management System for an offshore oil platform.
- ⇒ Used the ABB 800xA software suite to create logic and HMI graphics for real time operator recommendations

### **Education**

#### Memorial University of Newfoundland

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering Co-op Program Fifth Year, Expected Graduation April 2021

#### Technical

⇒ PCB Design ⇒ Embedded Systems ⇒ HDI Multilayer PCB ⇒ Microcontrollers  $\Rightarrow$  High Spd. Digital ⇒ Adv. Radio License Design and SI  $\Rightarrow$  3D-Printing  $\Rightarrow$  DVT & PVT ⇒ CAD Modeling ⇒ SMD Soldering

⇒ Debugging

# Software

⇒ Altium & KiCAD  $\Rightarrow$  C & C++

⇒ Matlab & Simulink ⇒ Mbed Framework  $\Rightarrow$  Python ⇒ AVR Assembler ⇒ SPICE Simulation  $\Rightarrow$  GIT, SVN ⇒ Solidworks ⇒ ABB 800xA

# Extracurricular

#### Paradigm Hyperloop - SpaceX Comp.

**Electrical Team** |Sept 2017 - May 2020

⇒ Sys. Design for 800V electric propulsion

⇒ 0.6kW PDB w/ LGA pkg design and assembly

#### **Memorial SAE Baja**

Electrical Lead |Jan 2018 - Jan 2020

- ⇒ Designed data acq. system & gauge cluster
- ⇒ FPV video sys. & LoRa communication

#### IEEE

Student Branch Chair |Jan 2017 – Jan 2020 ⇒ Lead student branch, PCB design workshops

# Projects

⇒ IOT Smart Home ⇒ AUV Senior Design ⇒ Nixie Tube Clock ⇒ Solar Tracking PCB ⇒ FPV Racing Quad ⇒ Auto Fish Feeder ⇒ PCB Reflow Oven ⇒ Emerg. Light System ⇒ Wireless PWR TX ⇒ Relay Arduino Shield

#### Interests

⇒ HAM Operator ⇒ Hiking  $\Rightarrow$  3D Printing ⇒ Electronics Hobbyist ⇒ Motorcycles ⇒ Wine Brewing  $\Rightarrow$  RC Vehicles  $\Rightarrow$  PCB Design (30+)

⇒ Foosball ⇒ Basketball